Guide to the Harold J. Gibson Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- DOCUMENTS RELATED TO THE ASSOCIATION OF MACHINISTS AND AEROSPACE WORKERS, DEMOCRATIC PARTY POLITICS, AND PERSONAL LIFE, c. 1910s-2012; SERIES 3 (Box-folder 3/17-8/16)
  - Democratic National Convention- Roll of Delegates, Platform, Party Invitations, 1956 (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Political Event Programs- Hubert Humphrey, Shop Committeeman Dinner, Jefferson-Jackson Day Speech, c. 1956 (Box-folder 7/17)
  - Vice President's Weekly Reports, 1964 (Box-folder 7/18)
  - Vice President's Weekly Reports, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 7/19)
  - Vice President's Weekly Reports, 1958 (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Expense Reimbursement Correspondence, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 7/21)
  - Vice President's Weekly Reports, 1961 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Vice President's Weekly Reports and Expense Correspondence, 1957 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Vice President's Weekly Reports, 1985 (Box-folder 7/24)
  - Pay Stubs- Helen and Harold Gibson, 1943-1955 (Box-folder 8/1)
  - International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers Convention Planning Information, Boeing 307 Stratoliner Print, Address/phone list, IAM Retired Staff Reunion, Obituary page, 1984-2006 (Box-folder 8/2)
  - District 571 Aero Mechanic, 1945-1991 (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Draft of the History of District Lodge 571 by Tom Tippett (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Draft of History of District Lodge 571 Continued, 'Portrait of a Trade Unionist'- Biography of Wabern Gartin, After 1981 (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Labor Relations Reporter- Decisions of the National Labor Relations Board, 1988 (Box-folder 8/6)
  - Job Erosion District 751- Union Erosion Committee, 1969-1977 (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Office Instructions, Employee Lists and Information, Contacts, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Pension Plan, 1956 (Box-folder 8/9)
  - Office and Professional Employees Local no. 8 Agreements, Constitution, Correspondence, Newspapers, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 8/10-11)
  - Office and Professional Employees, Local 8, Agreements, By-Laws, Meeting Minutes, Elections, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 8/12)
  - IAM Pension Fund, Medical Coverage Contract Information Helen Gibson, 1984-1993 (Box-folder 8/13)
  - Office and Professional Employees Union Local #8- Agreements, Correspondence, 1977-1985 (Box-folder 8/14)
  - Office and Professional Employees Union Local #8 Budget, Newsletters, Contracts, Papers re: Merger 1975-1988 (Box-folder 8/15)
  - Aero Mechanic- Harold Gibson Obituary, 1984 (Box-folder 8/16)
- NEWSPAPER AND SCRAPBOOK COLLECTION, 1939-1993; SERIES 4 (Box-folder 9/1-18/3)
  - The Aero Mechanic Annual, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 9/1)
  - The Aero Mechanic Aug '93 Article re: Wabern Gartin, Ed Carrig, Louie O'Callaghan, Harry Edwards, 1993 (Box-folder 9/2)
  - The IAM Machinist, Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 1957 (Box-folder 9/3)
  - IAM Machinist Newspaper, 1959 (Box-folder 9/4)
  - Aero Mechanic, Local Newspapers, 1959 (Box-folder 9/5)
  - IAM Machinist Newspaper, 1960 (Box-folder 9/6-7)
  - Aero Mechanic Newspaper, 1960 (Box-folder 9/8)
  - IAM Machinist Newspaper, 1961 (Box-folder 9/9)
  - Aero Mechanic Newspaper, 1961 (Box-folder 9/10)
  - IAM Machinist, Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 1962 (Box-folder 9/11)
  - IAM Machinist, Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 1963 (Box-folder 9/12)
  - IAM Machinist, Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 1964 (Box-folder 9/13)
  - IAM Machinist, Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 1965 (Box-folder 9/14)
  - IAM Machinist Newspaper, 1966 (Box-folder 9/15)
  - Aero Mechanic, Local Newspapers, 1966 (Box-folder 9/16)
  - IAM Machinist, Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 1969 (Box-folder 9/17)
  - IAM Machinist Newspaper, 1970 (Box-folder 9/18)
  - Aero Mechanic, Other Newspapers, 1970 (Box-folder 9/19)
  - IAM Machinist, Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 1971 (Box-folder 9/20)
  - Aero Mechanic Newspaper, 1980 (Box-folder 9/21)
  - IAM Machinist Newspaper, 1957 (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Aero Mechanic Newspaper, 1957 (Box-folder 10/2)
  - IAM Machinist Newspaper, 1958 (Box-folder 10/3)
  - Aero Mechanic, Local Newspapers, 1958 (Box-folder 10/4)
  - IAM Machinist, Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 1959 (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Aero Mechanic Newspaper, 1961 (Box-folder 10/6)
  - IAM Machinist Newspaper, 1961 (Box-folder 10/7-8)
  - IAM Machinist Newspaper, 1962 (Box-folder 10/9)
  - Loose Newspaper Clippings from Scrapbook- Including 1948 Strike (Box-folder 11/1)
  - Newspapers Covering WWII, Flying Fortress Production, WLB Conflict, 1943 (Box-folder 11/2)
  - Scrapbook- World War II Service and Return Home, 1948 Strike, Baseball, 1944-1948 (Box-folder 11/3)
  - Scrapbook- World War II Newspapers and 1948 Strike, conflict with War Labor Board, 1942-1948 (Box-folder 12/1)
  - Seattle Newspapers Re: WWII War Labor Board Disputes, 1943 (Box-folder 12/2)
  - Newspaper Collection, 1940s-1960s (Box-folder 13)
  - Union Shop Vote, Elections Newspaper Clippings 1950s (Box-folder 14/1)
  - Elections Fliers, World War II Bulletins, 1944-1961 (Box-folder 14/2)
  - Newspaper Collection 1940s-1960s (Wartime Papers, Recruitment) (Box-folder 14/3)
  - Telegrams, Election Fliers, Speeches, 1942 (Box-folder 15/1)
  - Newspaper Collection, Mostly WWII- Recruitment, War Labor Board, 1940-1965 (Box-folder 15/2)
  - Scrapbook of Newspaper Clippings from 1949 Boeing Strike, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 16)
  - Fliers, Strike Bulletin - 1948 Strike (Box-folder 17/1)
  - Photocopied pictures, Certificates of Committee Memberships, Awards, and Appreciations, 1954-1971 (Box-folder 17/2)
  - Newspaper Clippings- 1943 WWII and Flying Fortress Drive (Box-folder 17/3)
  - Rainier: The Epic of the Mountain by Dan Ward Gibson, Undated (Box-folder 17/4)
  - Print of Boeing B-17E Flying Fortress, c. 1943 (Box-folder 17/5)
  - Boeing Family Day Brochure, 1943 (Box-folder 17/6)
  - Seattle Post Intelligencer- Work Stoppage at Boeing, 1943 (Box-folder 17/7)
  - Seattle Daily Times- No Strike Monday at Boing, 1943 (Box-folder 17/8)
  - Seattle Post Intelligencer- Boeing Awarded New Contract for Huge Transports, 1945 (Box-folder 17/9)
  - Seattle Post Intelligencer- Boeing Plants Shut Down Indefinitely by Cutback, 1945 (Box-folder 17/10)
  - Seattle Daily Times- War Labor Board Racked by Strife, 1943 (Box-folder 17/11)
  - Seattle Post Intelligencer- Millions in Boeing Contracts Hinge on CAB Rulings, 1945 (Box-folder 17/12)
  - Seattle Post Intelligencer- Boeing Plans 2 New Planes For Commercial Transport, 1945 (Box-folder 17/13)
  - The Machinist Vol. 16, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 18/1)
  - The Machinist Vol. 17, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 18/2)
  - The Machinist Vol. 18, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 18/3)
- OBJECT COLLECTION, 1956-1980s; SERIES 5 (Box-folder 19/1-19/14)
  - Addressograph Proposal, 1963 (Box-folder 19/1)
  - Bag from IAM 26th G.L. Convention, Miami Beach, Florida, 1964 (Box-folder 19/2)
  - Bag from IAM 24th Convention San Francisco, CA, 1956 (Box-folder 19/3)
  - Bag, Machinists Non-Partisan Political League, Undated (Box-folder 19/4)
  - Bag from IAM 18th Convention, Los Angeles, CA, 1972 (Box-folder 19/5)
  - Travel Case- 25th IAM Convention, St. Louis, 1960-1972 (Box-folder 19/6)
  - Lodge 751 Clock, undated (Box-folder 19/7)
  - IAM Toolset, undated (Box-folder 19/8)
  - Copper Name Plate, undated (Box-folder 19/9)
  - Wallet from IAM 18th Convention, Los Angeles, CA, 1972 (Box-folder 19/10)
  - IAM Pins, 1970s-1980s (Box-folder 19/11)
  - Leather International Association of Machinists Sleeve, undated (Box-folder 19/12)
  - IAM Pen, undated (Box-folder 19/13)
  - Name Stamp, undated (Box-folder 19/14)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1940-1960s; SERIES 6 (Box-folder 19/15-19/22)
  - Photograph of Car with Sign, Re: Release of the Grand Lodge Auditors Report Issue, 1954-1959 (Box-folder 19/15)
  - King County National Defense Council Card, Issued August 20, 1940 (Box-folder 19/16)
  - Photograph of International Association of Machinists Rock Mosaic Emblem (Box-folder 19/17-18)
  - Photograph of Harold Gibson and William M. Allen (Boeing President), 1950s (Box-folder 19/19)
  - Photograph, Gibson and Unknown Man at Podium, 1960s (Box-folder 19/20-21)
  - Harold Gibson, C.L. Bentley (Grand Lodge Representative), and William M. Allen (Boeing President) Signing Contract, 1948 (Box-folder 19/22)